Guide to the Dr. Huey P. Newton Foundation Inc. Collection
Department of Special Collections
Dr. Huey P. Newton Foundation Inc. collection
1968-1994
M0864
Dr. Huey P. Newton Foundation, Inc.
100 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The Huey P. Newton Foundation was started by David Hilliard and Fredrika Newton to develop and sponsor cultural, historical and educational programs and institutions consistant with the theories and teaching of Huey Newton and the philosophy and ideology of the Black Panther Party. Huey P. Newton founded the Black Panther Party during the late 1960's to organize and train African Americans to protect themselves against official violence. As the Party evolved, Newton professed the development of programs for the Black community and the philosophy of self-help.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use. The Audio-Visual materials require at least three weeks advance notice to use in order to allow staff time to have use copies made from the original items.
Acquisition Information
Acquired from Dr. Huey P. Newton Foundation Inc.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Newton, Huey P.--Trials, litigation, etc.; Black Panther Party--History.; African Americans--Civil rights.; African Americans--History--1964-; Black power--United States.
Biography / Administrative History
In 1966 a group of young, African-American men attempting to organize the black community formed the Black Panther Party for Self-Defense and put forth their agenda in a document entitled "What We Want...What We Believe". The Party organized armed patrols, well-versed in civil rights, to protect their communities by monitoring the activities of the community law enforcement officers. Its leaders were Bobby Seale (Chairman of the Black Panther Party from 1966 -1974), Huey P. Newton (Minister of Defense from 1966 -1981), Eldridge Cleaver (Minister of Information), David Hilliard (Chief-of-Staff), and others.
The first office of the Black Panther Party was opened in Oakland, California on January 1, 1967. By November 1967 most of the Party members and leaders were incarcerated with Huey Newton being arrested for the shooting of an Oakland police officer. "Free Huey" rallies, the development of a Party newspaper and speaking engagements by members transformed the Party from a self-defense organization to a political one.
By 1968 the implementation of community programs took hold -free breakfasts for schoolchildren, medical clinics, schools, and political education classes for all members. Branches were developing around the nation. But the leadership was struggling with Newton still in jail and dealing with his many legal battles; Cleaver in exile; and Seale and Hilliard in and out of power. Federal and local law enforcement agencies, conscious of the growth and development of the organization, its continued armed police patrols, and its often violent methods began keeping photos and dossiers on various members and their activities.
By 1969 the Black Panther Party experienced further conflict; the infiltration of disguised police informants and ideological disagreement amongst the ranks created internal instability. Such disputes, however, were momentarily set aside when, in 1970, Huey P. Newton was freed from prison. With his conviction overturned, Newton returned to prominence as the Party's national leader, and community support grew once more.
A major faction of dissent, lead by Eldridge Cleaver, nevertheless had been firmly established in Newton's absence. Cleaver's dispute centered on the terms of revolution; whereas Newton saw revolution as a process, Cleaver advocated for immediate confrontation. The guns which Panthers first used as a tool for self-defence in 1966, in Cleaver's hands,offered as an ultimatum to society. Newton's philosophy of community service, by contrast, is reflected in the development of Survival Programs such as the Oakland Community School and Seniors Against a Fearful Environment. The Party expelled Cleaver and his comrades in 1972 1for the welfare of the organization and Black communities.
In 1973, the party experienced another crisis in leadership. Huey Newton fled into exile to Cuba rather than facing arrest and Bobby Seale decided to resign from the Black Panther Party. Elaine Brown assumed the position of chairman of the party and developed the community programs that were in existence. When Huey returned in 1977, the party again experienced a period of divided loyalties between favorite leaders and confusion reigned. By 1981 the final community school sponsored by the Party closed and the Black Panther Party came to an end.
Huey P. Newton was a strong force in the development of the Black Panther Party with his ideas and charisma. He received his Ph.D. from the University of California at Santa Cruz in 1980 and wrote several papers and books depicting his theories and his work within the party. After his death in 1989, the Huey P. Newton Foundation was started by David Hilliard and Fredrika Newton to develop and sponsor cultural, historical and educational programs and institutions consistent with the theories and teaching of Huey Newton and the philosophy and ideology of the Black Panther Party.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Huey P. Newton Foundation Records consists of files covering the time period from 1968 -1994 and includes the papers of Huey P. Newton, the Black Panther Party, David Hilliard, FBI papers acquired through the Freedom of Information Act, the Huey P. Newton Foundation, and photographs, audiovisual materials, printed matter and newspaper clippings from all aspects of the collection. There are personal items, correspondences, and internal documents within the organizations. Researchers can find legal files from many different cases, papers from classes that Huey Newton attended, manuscripts of writings by Huey Newton, David Hilliard, and members of the Black Panther Party, and information about programs that the Black Panther Party started (e.g. Oakland Community Schools, Community Survival Projects, health clinics). The financial aspects of the organization are covered in the records of the Stronghold Corp. and other financial materials and ventures. There is also a collection of reference and printed materials that were used by both the Party and Huey Newton.
The folders themselves are as the Foundation kept them and only arranged to fit into the proper series. Any organization within the folders is that of the person, Party, or the Foundation. In cases where there was no folder name, one was created and placed in brackets. Folders with different contents other than the given title were noted in the "Contents of Folder" field of the database. The Freedom of Information Act files were generally not in folders and so were organized by date.
Series Description and Container List
- Series 1: Huey P. Newton Papers, 1
  - Subseries 1: Personal, 1
    - Personal File Huey [Misc. Documents] [1 of 3]1976 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Huey P. Newton birth certificate;Armelie Newton's will
    - Personal File Huey [Misc. Documents] [2 of 3]1976 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Ankra Internation Corp. some photos soloar home information
    - Personal File Huey [Misc. Documents] [3 of 3]1976 - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Universal Foundation of Deliverence Income Tax information
    - Huey1973 - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      thank you cards;health records;tax records;teaching credential application
    - IRS to Huey P. Newton1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Contract for Seize the Time Book and Record Store in New York [Huey's poetry] (Box 1, Folder 6)
      poetry
    - Poems -- General [1 of 5]1970 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      poems by and to Huey and Gwen Fountaine birthday cards
    - Poems -- General [2 of 5]1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Poems -- General [3 of 5]1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Poems -- General [4 of 5]1970 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Poems -- General [5 of 5]1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Poems by Ericka1978 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Students Poems to HPN 1976 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Huey P. Newton - A Biography, by Paul Macchia, 19671967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Songs By Elaine (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Western Union Telegrams1971 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      telegrams from various people including John Lennon and Yoko Ono
    - Telegrams - Misc1969 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      telegrams regarding trials and FOIA
    - Western Union1977 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      various telegrams
    - Telegram from Willie Brown1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      actually a letter
    - 1971 Christmas Cards1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1973 Christmas Cards1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1974 Birthday Cards1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Congratulations Letters to HPN on PhD1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Invitations (general)1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Nomination of HPN to Rep. 7th District in Congress July, 19681968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - California National Guard Award to HPN1977 - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Universal Life Church Ordination of HPN (Document)1973, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Huey Newton Publicity1967 - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      various notes, a letter and a flyer
    - "Who's Who" Books Huey is In1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Letters Honoring HPN1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      announcement for inclusion in "The Ebony Success Library"
    - Bert Schneider 1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      notes and articles from Bert and Judy Schneider to HPN.
    - Karen Wald1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      correspondence re: BPP internal issues
    - Contracts Out 1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      correspondence to HPN from Karen Wald re: BPP internal issues
    - Martin Luther King, Jr.1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Cuba [1 of 2]1975 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Cuba [2 of 2]1975 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - July 3, 1977 return to the U.S.1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Servant: Post Exile [1 of 3]1975 - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Cuban exile, legal docs.
    - Servant: Post Exile [2 of 3]1975 - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Servant: Post Exile [3 of 3]1975 - 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Deekshant Rajneesh Center (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Huey P. Newton Documents: Seven Days Catalog Blank Letterhead Flyers1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - ["For Hugh Morris Freed-- and all the others" autographed copy] (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Various Cards from Lebanon (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Guerilla Television" by Michael Shamberg and Raindance Corporation 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: Correspondence, 2
    - Huey's Personal File [1 of 5]1971 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Huey's Personal File [2 of 5]1971 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Huey's Personal File [3 of 5]1971 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Huey's Personal File [4 of 5]1971 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Huey's Personal File [5 of 5]1971 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - [Personal correspondence from Gwen Newton] (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence to Huey (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Letters Sent to Huey --Old [1 of 2]1970 - 1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Letters Sent to Huey --Old [2 of 2]1970 - 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Action Program for WOPC (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Betty Davis (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Fred J. Hiestand, Esq. [1 of 3]1972 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Fred J. Hiestand, Esq. [2 of 3]1972 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Fred J. Hiestand, Esq. [3 of 3]1972 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Republic of Cuba Havana, Cuba From Fred Hiestand (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence from Don Hopkins1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Eve Kennelly1972; 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Huey P. Newton's Correspondence to President Khadafi 1986 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Booker T. Lewis, Jr. [1 of 3]1973 - 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Booker T. Lewis, Jr. [2 of 3]1973 - 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Booker T. Lewis, Jr. [3 of 3]1973 - 1979 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Letter From Booker to Huey June 23, 19801980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Follow-up Letters From Lubell: Re: Requests for an interview with Huey1971 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - National Lawyers Guild [Statement of Paul Harris];1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - North Peralta Community College 1973 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Letter to Bro. David Sibeko (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Sunrise Grocery Catalog/Sangha Food Cooperative/Joshua Goldstein [1 of 3] (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Sunrise Grocery Catalog/Sangha Food Cooperative/Joshua Goldstein [2 of 3] (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sunrise Grocery Catalog/Sangha Food Cooperative/Joshua Goldstein [3 of 3] (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Fred Wyatt1971 - 1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1977-1978 Other Students Correspondence (requests, etc.)1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Community Support Letters [re: Huey] [1 of 2] [oversize]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Community Support Letters [re: Huey] [2 of 2] [oversize]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Letters of Support -- Form 1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Corresp - Committee to Support the BPP - From Japan (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Letters/Correspondence From-With Attorneys HPN (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Requests for Huey to indorse books 1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - IRTH Final Proposal to NEH (To Huey)1981 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Prison Information1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Prison Info. ;1976 - 1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence.1968 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Letters to Huey P. Newton1968 - 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Letters [1972-1985] (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - HPN - Misc. Letters1978 - 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Letters [1971 - 1973; 1980] [1 of 2]1971 - 1973; 1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Letters [1971 - 1973; 1980] [2 of 2]1971 - 1973; 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Hate Mail / Criticism [1 of 2]1971 - 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Hate Mail / Criticism [2 of 2]1971 - 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Hate Mail1977 - 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [1 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [2 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [3 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [4 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [5 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [6 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [7 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [8 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [9 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [10 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [11 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [12 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [13 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [14 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [15 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [16 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [17 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [18 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [19 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [20 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [21 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [22 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [23 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [24 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [25 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Letters Not to be Answered [26 of 26]1971 - 1973 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - General Letters Not Answered [1 of 5] [oversize]1977 - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - General Letters Not Answered [2 of 5] [oversize]1977 - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - General Letters Not Answered [3 of 5] [oversize]1977 - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - General Letters Not Answered [4 of 5] [oversize]1977 - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - General Letters Not Answered [5 of 5] [oversize]1977 - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - [Unopened correspondence 1989 May 15 - April 15]1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - [Unopened correspondence 1989 April 20 -27]1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - [Unopened correspondence 1989 May 11 - June 4]1989 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - [Unopened correspondence 1989 June 16 - 30]1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - [Unopened correspondence 1989 July 1 - 15]1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - [Unopened correspondence 1989 July 24 - 31]1989 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - [Unopened correspondence 1989 July 24 - 31]1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - [Unopened correspondence 1989 August 2 - 4]1989 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - [Unopened correspondence 1989 August 7 - n.d]1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Poems - General1970 (Othertype 60, Folder 1)
    - General letters answered1979 (Othertype 60, Folder 2)
    - Betty Davis1970 (Othertype 60, Folder 3)
    - Community Support Letter1977 - 1978 (Othertype 60, Folder 4)
    - Bert Schneider1971 - 1972 (Othertype 60, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3: Legal Papers, 3
    - People v. Newton #8590 Index1967 - 1969 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - HPN - List of Legal Files1971 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Case # 8590
    - People vs. Newton #8590 1964 Prior Felony Conviction (#I) [1 of 2]1964 - 1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - People vs. Newton #8590 1964 Prior Felony Conviction (#I) [2 of 2]1964 - 1967 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Newton, Huey CRG #8590 Investigation - See list of contents (1) [1 of 2]1967 - 1969 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Newton, Huey CRG #8590 Investigation - See list of contents (1) [2 of 2]1967 - 1969 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Newton, Huey Evidence CRG #8590 (2) 1967 - 1969 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Correspondence Nov. 1967 - Oct. 1968 (2) [2 of 5]1967 - 1968 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Correspondence Nov. 1967 - Oct. 1968 (2) [3 of 5]1967 - 1968 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Correspondence Nov. 1967 - Oct. 1968 (2) [4 of 5]1967 - 1968 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Correspondence Nov. 1967 - Oct. 1968 (2) [5 of 5]1967 - 1968 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Correspondence Oct 1968- August 1969 (2b) [1 of 2]1968 - 1969 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Correspondence Oct 1968- August 1969 (2b) [2 of 2]1968 - 1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Correspondence August 1969 - present (2 c) [1 of 2)1969 - 1980 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Correspondence August 1969 - present (2 c) [2 of 2)1969 - 1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Voir Dire - Cases, Writings etc. (3) [1 of 5]1961 - 1969 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Voir Dire - Cases, Writings etc. (3) [2 of 5]1961 - 1969 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Voir Dire - Cases, Writings etc. (3) [3 of 5]1961 - 1969 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Correspondence Nov. 1967 - Oct. 1968 (2) [1 of 5]1967 - 1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Voir Dire - Cases, Writings etc. (3) [4 of 5]1961 - 1969 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Voir Dire - Cases, Writings etc. (3) [5 of 5]1961 - 1969 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Newton, Huey Lab. Reports CRG #8590 (3) [1 of 2] (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Newton, Huey Lab. Reports CRG #8590 (3) [2 of 2] (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Newton, Huey Other Convictions CRG #8590 (4)1971 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Huey P. Newton Personal (5) [1 of 5]1968 - 1981 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Huey P. Newton Personal (5) [2 of 5]1968 - 1981 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Huey P. Newton Personal (5) [3 of 5]1968 - 1981 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Huey P. Newton Personal (5) [4 of 5]1968 - 1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Huey P. Newton Personal (5) [5 of 5]1968 - 1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - People v. Huey Newton #8590 Heanes and Frey Research (6) [1 of 2]1966 - 1968 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - People v. Huey Newton #8590 Heanes and Frey Research (6) [2 of 2]1966 - 1968 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Newton, Huey CRG #8590 Challenge for Cause-See list of contents (6)1967 - 1971 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Witnesses and Research Literature (7) [1 of 3]1968 - 1969 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Witnesses and Research Literature (7) [2 of 3]1968 - 1969 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Witnesses and Research Literature (7) [3 of 3]1968 - 1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Pre-Trial 1967 (8) [1 of 3]1967 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Pre-Trial 1967 (8) [2 of 3]1967 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Pre-Trial 1967 (8) [3 of 3]1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Trial July 1968 (9) [1 of 3]1965 - 1968 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Trial July 1968 (9) [2 of 3]1965 - 1968 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Trial July 1968 (9) [3 of 3]1965 - 1968 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Newton, Huey Testimony of Trial CRG #8590 (10) 1968 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - People v. Newton #8590 v. Mc Kinney, Gene Allen Writ of Habeas Corpus, etc. (10) [1 of 2]1968 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - People v. Newton #8590 v. Mc Kinney, Gene Allen Writ of Habeas Corpus, etc. (10) [2 of 2]1968 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Bail on Appeal - Cases and Research (11) [1 of 3]1968 - 1969 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Bail on Appeal - Cases and Research (11) [2 of 3]1968 - 1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Bail on Appeal - Cases and Research (11) [3 of 3]1968 - 1969 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Newton, Huey CRG #8590 Jury(12) [1 of 2]1970 - 1971 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Newton, Huey CRG #8590 Jury (12) [2 of 2]1970 - 1971 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Newton, Huey Jury Instructions CRG #8590 (13) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Appeal from Superior Court Convict. (13);[1 of 4]1969 - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Appeal from Superior Court Convict. (13);[2 of 4]1969 - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Appeal from Superior Court Convict. (13);[3 of 4]1969 - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - People v. Newton #8590 Appeal from Superior Court Convict. (13);[4 of 4]1969 - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - People v. Newton Parole #8590 (14)1969 - 1970 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Newton, Huey CRG #8590 Transcripts - See list of contents (14)1964 - 1971 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - [1974 cases Huey: People vs. Newton Re-Trial (15) #8590] 1974; 1970; 1980 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Peo. v. Newton #8590 CRG Mandamus Pleadings & Appeal (16)1967 - 1968 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Newton, Huey P. Jury (2nd trial - July 1971) #8590 CRG (17)1971 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Newton, Huey Miscellaneous CRG #8590 (17) 1967 - 1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Newton, Huey #8590 FM Bail Pending New Trial (18) [1 of 2]1970 - 1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Newton, Huey #8590 FM Bail Pending New Trial (18) [2 of 2]1970 - 1971 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Newton, Huey P. Motion for Discovery; Writ of Prohibition Writ of Supersedeas CRG (22) [1 of 4]1971 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Cases #30425, #7753
    - Newton, Huey P. Motion for Discovery; Writ of Prohibition Writ of Supersedeas CRG (22) [2 of 4]1971 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Newton, Huey P. Motion for Discovery; Writ of Prohibition Writ of Supersedeas CRG (22) [3 of 4]1971 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Newton, Huey P. Motion for Discovery; Writ of Prohibition Writ of Supersedeas CRG (22) [4 of 4]1971 (Box 16, Folder 11)